A Guide to the Deisher-Strickland Account Book and Papers, 1829-1876
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Deisher-Strickland Account Book and Papers 1829-1876
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
38-20
This collection consists of ca. 17 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was purchased by the University Library prior to 1938.
Scope and Content
The Deisher-Strickland volume contains accounts of George Deisher, a blacksmith or wheelwright, 1829-1830, and dealer in miscellaneous groceries and carpentry, 1831-1843, at an unspecified place.
The volume continues with accounts of Henry S. Strickland of Moffat's Creek, Augusta County, Va., a dealer in groceries and miscellaneous commodities, 1843-1872, who had married Deisher's widow, Elizabeth. The volume also contains an appraisal bill of the etate of George [Durham?]
Miscellaneous items from the volume include loose bills, receipts, and letters of Strickland and Elizabeth Deisher Strickland; depositions of Strickland, his wife and her daughter regarding the estate of Deisher; and a Rockbridge County real estate agreement.
Contents List
- Account Book 1829-1830
  The volume contains accounts of George Deischer, a blacksmith or wheelwright, during 1829-1830, and his accounts as a dealer in miscellaneous groceries and carpentry, 1831-1843. The place of his business is not identified. The volume continues with the accounts of Henry S. Strickland of Moffat's Creek, Augusta County, Virginia, as a dealer in groceries and miscellaneous commodities, 1843-1872. At a date unknown, [ca. 1861?], Strickland had married Deisher's widow, Elizabeth.
  Items included in the volume apparently unrelated to the accounts are an appraisal bill of the estate of George [Durham?], 14 October 1842, and miscellaneous notes, 1866-1872.
- Loose Papers
  - A bill, [W.] M. McCauley to Henry Strickland 186[ ] January 22, ADS
  - Blacksmithing account, Henry Strickland with [John Benson] 1865, AD
  - [?] Morgan, Staunton, Va., to Henry S. Strickland, Moffatt's Creek, Augusta County, Va., enclosing payment for cattle. 1868 September 17, ALS
  - W. A. Anderson, Richmond, Va., to Henry S. Strickland, regarding claim against Mays & Rudisill. 1871 December 14, ALS
  - Depositions of Henry Strickland, his wife, Elizabeth (widow of George Deisher), and Mary Ann Deisher (daughter of George and Elizabeth Deisher) regarding the estate of George Deisher and the failure of Fletcher H. Mays, Special Commisioner, to settle the estate [dating as early as 1861]. ca. 1872, ADSs
  - Article of agreement to convey real estate, Samuel S. Mynes and Jacob A. Wiseman, both of Rockbridge County, Va. 1873 March 14, DS
  - James M. Bolton, New Goshen, Indiana, to his uncle, Henry S. Strickland, concerning crops. 1873 June 10, ALS
  - Samuel B. Morrison to Mr. Robinson, Steeles Mill, [Va.], concerning Henry S. Strickland and flour. 1873 June 18, ALS
  - [ ? ] to [Henry S.] Strickland, concerning payment for a wheel. 1873 June 27, ALS
  - Elizabeth Strickland, et al, to Henry Miller, Overseer of Roads in Rockbridge County, et al, denying access to property until assessed damages are paid. (Copy by John Wiseman.) 1874 May 27, AL copy
  - Jno. Waldrop, Swoopes, [Va.], to Elizabeth Strickland, Moffatt's Creek, Va., concerning her order for shingles. 1876 July 22, ALS
  - T. L. Hailman, Moffatt's Creek, Va., to Mrs. Strickland, concerning settlement of his account. 1876 August 18, ALS
  - Letter to Georgiana Strickland, Belleview Seminary from her parents, advising her that Betty is seriously ill with diphtheria and wants to see her, but the doctor advises against a visit. n.d., AL
  - Miscellaneous accounts, fragments and printed items n.d., ADSs